Finding Aid for the Getty Research Institute Scholars Program Images and Recordings, 1985-2013 IA20026
Institutional Records and Archives
- Audio recordings, 1987-2001; Series I.; 21.7 Linear Feet (27 boxes); 1741.37 GB (944 files)
  - Scholar Year 1996-1997, Series I.K.; 175.08 GB (87 files)
    Materials comprise audio recordings of events, lectures, and discussions held at the Getty during the scholar year 1996/1997. During this time Getty scholars explored the theme Perspectives on Los Angeles: Narratives, Images, History, which was devoted to research on Los Angeles and to comparative projects that viewed the city in relationship to other hemispheric and global sites. Scholars in residence had the opportunity to participate in a number of corollary programs developed by the Research Institute on issues of identity, community, and public culture, as well as programs having to do with preservation, resource development, and the comparative study of cities in the Americas at the turn of the century. A series of lectures was also presented in anticipation of the J. Paul Getty Museum's 1999 exhibition "Dosso Dossi, Court Painter in Renaissance Ferrara."
    The recordings are grouped first by symposia/theme, followed by a group of more general lectures and presentations. Within each group, the recordings are listed in chronological order.
    - Dosso Dossi and His Age, Series I.K.1.
      Materials comprise audio recordings of a series of lectures organized by the Getty Research Institute to examine Dosso's style, artistic influences, iconography, and historical context. The lectures continued a series begun in 1996 and anticipated the 1999 Getty Museum exhibition, "Dosso Dossi, Court Painter in Renaissance Ferrara."
      - Dosso Dossi, Seminar 1, March 4, 1997; (5 audiocassettes) (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
        - Part 1, 0967a (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
        - Part 2, 0967b (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
        - Part 3, 0968a (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
        - Part 4, 0968b (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
        - Part 5, 0969a (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
        - Part 6, 0969b (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
        - Part 7, 0970a (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
        - Part 8, 0970b (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
        - Part 9, 0971 (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
      - Dosso Dossi, Seminar 2, April 3-4, 1997; (4 audiocassettes) (Box 1996.IA.02-23)
        - Part 1, 0972a (Box 1996.IA.02-23)
        - Part 2, 0972b (Box 1996.IA.02-23)
        - Part 3, 0973a (Box 1996.IA.02-23)
        - Part 4, 0973b (Box 1996.IA.02-23)
        - Part 5, 0974a (Box 1996.IA.02-23)
        - Part 6, 0974b (Box 1996.IA.02-23)
        - Part 7, 0975 (Box 1996.IA.02-23)
      - Dosso Dossi, Seminar 3, May 4, 1997; (3 audiocassettes) (Box 1996.IA.02-23)
        - Part 1, 0858a (Box 1996.IA.02-23)
        - Part 2, 0858b (Box 1996.IA.02-23)
        - Part 3, 0859a (Box 1996.IA.02-23)
        - Part 4, 0859b (Box 1996.IA.02-23)
        - Part 5, 0860a (Box 1996.IA.02-23)
        - Part 6, 0860b (Box 1996.IA.02-23)
    - Lectures and presentations, Series I.K.2.
      Materials comprise audio recordings of events, lectures, and discussions held at the Getty during the scholar year 1996/1997. During this time Getty scholars explored the theme Perspectives on Los Angeles: Narratives, Images, History, which was devoted to research on Los Angeles and to comparative projects that viewed the city in relationship to other hemispheric and global sites. Scholars in residence had the opportunity to participate in a number of corollary programs developed by the Research Institute on issues of identity, community, and public culture, as well as programs having to do with preservation, resource development, and the comparative study of cities in the Americas at the turn of the century.
      - Hatoum, Mona. Lecture, September 10, 1996; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-21)
        - Part 1, 0765a (Box 1996.IA.02-21)
        - Part 2, 0765b (Box 1996.IA.02-21)
      - Hartog, Francois. "Times of Patrimony: A History of Cultural Legacies,", September 26, 1996; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
        - Hartog, Francois. Part 1, 0767a (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
        - Discussion. Part 2, 0767b (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
      - Lang, Karen. "A Question of Monumentality: The 1907 Bismarck National Monument Competition in Germany," Work in Progress Lecture, October 25, 1996; (2 audiocassettes) (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
        - Part 1, 0778a (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
        - Part 2, 0778b (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
        - Part 3, 0779 (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
      - Gossman, Lionel. "Kulturgeschichte, Kunstgeschichte, Genuss: History and Art in Jacob Burckhardt,", October 31, 1996; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
        - Gossman, Lionel. Part 1, 0784a (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
        - Discussion. Part 2, 0784b (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
      - Langdale, Allan. "The Rise of the Social History of Art in England, 1960-1978," Work In Progress Lecture, November 8, 1996; (2 audiocassettes) (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
        - Langdale, Allan. Part 1, 0785 (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
        - Discussion. Part 2, 0786 (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
      - Whiting, Cecile. "Trompe l'oeil Painting and the Counterfeit Civil War," Work in Progress Lecture, November 22, 1996; (2 audiocassettes) (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
        - Part 1, 0793 (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
        - Part 2, 0794 (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
      - Settis, Salvatore. "The Metamorphosis of Laocoon: From Marble to Bronze, From Bronze to Marble,", December 5, 1996; (2 audiocassettes) (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
        - Settis, Salvatore. Part 1, 0797 (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
        - Discussion. Part 2, 0798 (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
      - Bohme, Hartmut. "In the Interior of Modernity: The Fetish - Karl Marx's Fetishism Concept and its Context," Construction of Historical Meaning lecture, December 10, 1996; (2 audiocassettes) (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
        - Bohme, Hartmut. Part 1, 0799 (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
        - Discussion. Part 2, 0800 (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
      - Greenwood, Roberta. "Digging for History: The Recovery of Meaning," Construction of Historical Meaning series, January 23, 1997; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
        - Part 1, 0807a (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
        - Part 2, 0807b (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
      - Schoell-Glass, Charlotte. "In Search of an Answer to the 'Jewish Question': Aby Warburg's Cultural Science and Anti-Semitism," Construction of Historical Meaning series, January 30, 1997; (2 audiocassettes) (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
        - Part 1, 0810 (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
        - Part 2, 0811 (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
      - Scott, Joan Wallach. "The Fantasy of Feminist History," Construction of Historical Meaning series, February 6, 1997; (2 audiocassettes) (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
        - Part 1, 0814 (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
        - Part 2, 0815 (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
      - Fried, Michael. "Some Thoughts on Caravaggio," Construction of Historical Meaning series, February 20, 1997; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
        - Part 1, 0820a (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
        - Part 2, 0820b (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
      - Minsky, Marvin. "Art as a Theory of Perceptual Processes," Construction of Historical Meaning series, February 27, 1997; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
        - Part 1, 0823a (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
        - Part 2, 0823b (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
      - Troy, Nancy, Jim Herbert and Richard Myer. Works in Progress Lecture, February 28, 1997; (2 audiocassettes) (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
        - Troy, Nancy, Jim Herbert and Richard Myer. Part 1, 0824a (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
        - Troy, Nancy, Jim Herbert and Richard Myer. Part 2, 0824b (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
        - Discussion. Part 3, 0825 (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
      - Flick, Robbert, Dorothy Crawford, Harold Zellman and Michael Roth. KKGO Radio Interview, March 2, 1997; 0826; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
      - Fieback, Joachim. "Performance and Politics in Africa," Construction of Historical Meaning series, March 4, 1997; (2 audiocassettes) (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
        - Part 1, 0827 (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
        - Part 2, 0828 (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
      - Winther, Bert and Tamaki K. Brown. "Illegible Calligraphy and Dysfunctional Pottery: Modernizing Traditional Arts in Early Postwar Japan," Works in Progress lecture, March 14, 1997; (2 audiocassettes) (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
        - Part 1, 0833a (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
        - Part 2, 0833b (Box 1996.IA.02-23)
        - Part 3, 0834 (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
      - Winner, Mathias. "Raphael's Parnassus,", March 18, 1997; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-23)
        - Part 1, 0835a (Box 1996.IA.02-23)
        - Part 2, 0835b (Box 1996.IA.02-22)
      - Leys, Ruth. "Imitation Magic: Sandor Ferenczi on the Meaning of Psychic Trauma,", March 20, 1997; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-23)
        - Part 1, 0838a (Box 1996.IA.02-23)
        - Part 2, 0838b (Box 1996.IA.02-23)
      - Lewis, Samella. Construction of Historical Meaning series lecture, March 27, 1997; (2 audiocassettes) (Box 1996.IA.02-23)
        - Part 1, 0839 (Box 1996.IA.02-23)
        - Part 2, 0840 (Box 1996.IA.02-23)
      - Walker, Janet. "The Traumatic Paradox: Documentary Films, Historical Fictions and Cataclysmic Past Events," Construction of Historical Meaning series, April 3, 1997; 0843; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-23)
      - Ethington, Phillip. "Space-Time Integration: New Conceptual Tools for Creating Very Large Digital Archives,", April 10, 1997; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-23)
        - Part 1, 0845a (Box 1996.IA.02-23)
        - Part 2, 0845b (Box 1996.IA.02-23)
      - Woods-Marsden, Joanna. "The Visual Construction of Artistic Identity in the Renaissance: Self-Portraiture and Social Status of the Artist,", April 11, 1997; 0846; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-23)
        Audio file is incomplete. Only 3 minutes of audio.
      - Zellman, Harold and Roger Friedland. "Broadacre in Brentwood?: Thinking about the Politics of Residential Modernism,", April 16, 1997; (2 audiocassettes) (Box 1996.IA.02-23)
        - Part 1, 0847a (Box 1996.IA.02-23)
        - Part 2, 0847b (Box 1996.IA.02-23)
        - Part 3, 0848 (Box 1996.IA.02-23)
          Audio is cut-off at the end.
      - Holly, Michael Ann. "The Art of Melancholy,", April 17, 1997; (2 audiocassettes) (Box 1996.IA.02-23)
        - Part 1, 0849a (Box 1996.IA.02-23)
        - Part 2, 0849b (Box 1996.IA.02-23)
      - Lowe, Rick. "Rooted in a Vision of Change and Revolution: Watts House and Project Row Houses,", April 27, 1997; (2 audiocassettes) (Box 1996.IA.02-23)
        - Part 1, 0851 (Box 1996.IA.02-23)
        - Part 2, 0852 (Box 1996.IA.02-23)
      - James, David and Robert Carringer. Film Screening discussion, "My Brother's Wedding" by Charles Burnett, April 28, 1997; 0853 (Box 1996.IA.02-23)
        Did not save. Audio files have no sound or is not recoverable.
      - Flamming, Douglas. "African-Americans and the Making of L.A., 1890-1940,", April 30, 1997; (2 audiocassettes) (Box 1996.IA.02-23)
        - Part 1, 0854a (Box 1996.IA.02-23)
        - Part 2, 0854b (Box 1996.IA.02-23)
        - Part 3, 0855 (Box 1996.IA.02-23)
      - Dear, Michael. "Is there an L.A. School of Urbanism?", May 1, 1997; (2 audiocassettes) (Box 1996.IA.02-23)
        - Part 1, 0856 (Box 1996.IA.02-23)
        - Part 2, 0857 (Box 1996.IA.02-23)
      - Hondagnew-Sotelo, Pierrette. "Maid in L.A.,", May 7, 1997; (3 audiocassettes) (Box 1996.IA.02-23)
        - Part 1, 0861 (Box 1996.IA.02-23)
        - Part 2, 0862 (Box 1996.IA.02-23)
      - Rosenthal, Margaret. "Italian Style: A German Traveller's Collection of Fashionable Images in 1595," Works in Progress Lecture, May 9, 1997; (2 audiocassettes) (Box 1996.IA.02-23)
        - Part 1, 0864a (Box 1996.IA.02-23)
        - Part 2, 0864b (Box 1996.IA.02-23)
        - Part 3, 0865 (Box 1996.IA.02-23)
      - Butler, Octavia. Last Scholar Lecture at 401 Wilshire, May 13, 1997; 0866; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-23)
  - Scholar Year 1997-1998, 1998-1999; Series I.L.; 215.37 GB (91 files)
    Materials comprise audio recordings of events, lectures, and discussions held at the Getty during the scholar years 1997/1998 and 1998/1999. During this time Getty scholars explored the theme of the residential scholar program Representing the Passions and studied the ways in which strong, ungovernable emotions have been represented and classified in the arts throughout the history of the arts and humanities. This theme focused on the social need to name the passions (thus distinguishing them from one another) and to develop gestural and rhetorical conventions and codes in reference to them, while simultaneously noting how the ungovernability of the passions threatens either to break through or to be lost by the cultural conventions and codes that attempt to ritualize and control them. Theorists of human nature, language, and politics have wrestled with the challenge of the ungovernability of the passions since antiquity and the challenge continues to confront contemporary painters, actors, writers, and musicians.
    - Construction of Historical Meaning, 1998-1999; Series I.L.1.; (18 audiocassettes)
      Materials comprise 1998-1999 audio recordings of the Getty-sponsored lecture series "Construction of Historical Meaning," which focused on how artifacts, events, places, and people are understood when considered historically.
      - Berenbaum, Michael. Construction of Historical Meaning Lecture, April 21, 1998; 989 (Box 1996.IA.02-24)
        Audio file(s) not found.
      - Crimp, Douglas. Construction of Historical Meaning Lecture, May 21, 1998; (2 audiocassettes) (Box 1996.IA.02-24)
        - Part 1, 0887 (Box 1996.IA.02-24)
        - Part 2, 0888 (Box 1996.IA.02-24)
      - Stern, Leslie. Construction of Historical Meaning Lecture, September 24, 1998; 0991; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-24)
      - Adesokan, Akin. "In Search of 'New' Illusions: One Writer's Continuing Education,", October 8, 1998; 0992; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-24)
      - Roth, Michael. Construction of Historical Meaning Lecture, November 16, 1998; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-24)
        - Part 1, 0994a (Box 1996.IA.02-24)
        - Part 2, 0994b (Box 1996.IA.02-24)
      - Buerkle, Darcy. Construction of Historical Meaning Lecture, December 1, 1998; 0996; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-24)
      - Libeskind, Daniel. Construction of Historical Meaning Lecture, December 10, 1998; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-24)
        - Part 1, 0997a (Box 1996.IA.02-24)
        - Part 2, 0997b (Box 1996.IA.02-24)
      - Smith, Pamela. Construction of Historical Meaning Lecture, December 15, 1998; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-25)
        - Part 1, 0998a (Box 1996.IA.02-25)
        - Part 2, 0998b (Box 1996.IA.02-25)
      - Bal, Mieke. Construction of Historical Meaning Lecture, January 29, 1999; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-25)
        - Part 1, 0999a (Box 1996.IA.02-25)
        - Part 2, 0999b (Box 1996.IA.02-25)
      - Warner, Marina. "Darkness Visible in the Mind's Eye," Construction of Historical Meaning Lecture, February 18, 1999; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-25)
        - Part 1, 1000a (Box 1996.IA.02-25)
        - Part 2, 1000b (Box 1996.IA.02-25)
      - Kuivilar, Ron. Construction of Historical Meaning Lecture, March 8, 1999; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-25)
        - Part 1, 1003a (Box 1996.IA.02-25)
        - Part 2, 1003b (Box 1996.IA.02-25)
      - Brooks, Peter. "History of Painting," Construction of Historical Meaning Lecture, March 10, 1999; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-25)
        - Part 1, 1004a (Box 1996.IA.02-25)
        - Part 2, 1004b (Box 1996.IA.02-25)
      - Feldman, Allen. Construction of Historical Meaning Lecture [regarding the South African Truth and Reconciliation Commission], April 26, 1999; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-25)
        - Part 1, 1013a (Box 1996.IA.02-25)
        - Part 2, 1013b (Box 1996.IA.02-25)
      - Gourevitch, Philip. "Rwanda's False Histories: The Logic of Genocide," Construction of Historical Meaning Lecture, May 3, 1999; 1014; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-25)
      - Settis, Salvatore. Construction of Historical Meaning Lecture, May 20, 1999; (2 audiocassettes) (Box 1996.IA.02-25)
        - Part 1, 1017 (Box 1996.IA.02-25)
        - Part 2, 1018 (Box 1996.IA.02-25)
      - Young, James. Construction of Historical Meaning Lecture, June 7, 1999; (2 audiocassettes) (Box 1996.IA.02-25)
        - Part 1, 1019 (Box 1996.IA.02-25)
        - Part 2, 1020 (Box 1996.IA.02-25)
    - Contemporary Artistic Practices, 1998-1999; Series I.L.2.; (7 audiocassettes)
      Materials comprise 1998-1999 audio recordings of a Getty-sponsored lecture series in which practicing artists discuss various aspects of contemporary artistic practices.
      - de la Torre, Milagros. Contemporary Artistic Practices Lecture, February 26, 1998; 0878; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-24)
      - Tiravanija, Rirkrit. Contemporary Artistic Practices Lecture, March 26, 1998; 0880; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-24)
      - Wall, Jeff. Contemporary Artistic Practices Lecture, April 30, 1998; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-24)
        - Part 1, 0884a (Box 1996.IA.02-24)
        - Part 2, 0884b (Box 1996.IA.02-24)
      - Min, Yong Soon. Contemporary Artistic Practices Lecture, May 26, 1998; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-24)
        - Part 1, 0889a (Box 1996.IA.02-24)
        - Part 2, 0889b (Box 1996.IA.02-24)
      - Melamid, Alexis. Contemporary Artistic Practices Lecture, October 19, 1998; 0894; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-24)
      - Kaprow, Alan. "Enough Said," Contemporary Artistic Practice Lecture, April 8, 1999; 1007; (2 audiocassettes) (Box 1996.IA.02-25)
    - Interpreting El Lissitzky: New Perspectives, December 7-8, 1998; Series I.L.3.; (5 audiocassettes)
      Materials comprise audio recordings of lectures from a 1998 Getty Research Institute conference titled "Interpreting El Lissitzky: New Perspectives." In these lectures an international group of scholars examine works by El Lissitzky, one of the most influential artists of the early 20th-century Russian avant-garde. Scholars discuss his book designs, demonstration spaces, photographs, and the propaganda billboard, in order to assess the importance of underlying threads that hold his diverse career together. The conference was held in conjunction with the Getty's exhibition, "Monuments of the Future": Designs by El Lissitzky, which opened in November, 1998.
      - Day One:, December 7, 1998; (3 audiocassettes) (Box 1996.IA.02-24)
        - Part 1, 0896a (Box 1996.IA.02-24)
        - Part 2, 0896b (Box 1996.IA.02-24)
        - Part 3, 0897a (Box 1996.IA.02-24)
        - Part 4, 0897b (Box 1996.IA.02-24)
        - Part 5, 0898 (Box 1996.IA.02-24)
      - Day Two:, December 8, 1998; (2 audiocassettes) (Box 1996.IA.02-24)
        - Part 1, 0899a (Box 1996.IA.02-24)
        - Part 2, 0899b (Box 1996.IA.02-24)
        - Part 3, 0900 (Box 1996.IA.02-24)
    - Mapping L.A.: A Global Prototype symposium, June 7-8, 1999; Series I.L.4.; (7 audiocassettes)
      Materials comprise audio recordings of the 1999 symposium "Mapping L.A.: A Global Prototype," which was designed to spotlight the archives of Southern California and celebrate the publication: "Cultural Inheritance LA: A Directory of Less-Visible Archives and Collections in the Los Angeles Region." The symposium was part of the L.A. as Subject collaboration. The first day of the symposium was by invitation only and had a scholarly and theoretical focus. Day One featured keynote speaker Angela Oh and included a videoconference panel discussion with Prague regarding the Stories Exchange Project. The second day was open to the public and featured professional archivists, curators, and historians who shared information about preserving and displaying collections. Day Two speakers included Janet Fireman, Robert Gottlieb, Ruben Martinez and others.
      - Session One:, June 7, 1999; (4 audiocassettes) (Box 1996.IA.02-25)
        - Part 1, 1021a (Box 1996.IA.02-25)
        - Part 2, 1021b (Box 1996.IA.02-25)
        - Part 3, 1022 (Box 1996.IA.02-25)
        - Part 4, 1023 (Box 1996.IA.02-25)
        - Part 5, 1024 (Box 1996.IA.02-25)
      - Session Two:, June 8, 1999; (3 audiocassettes) (Box 1996.IA.02-25)
        - Part 1, 1025a (Box 1996.IA.02-25)
        - Part 2, 1025b (Box 1996.IA.02-25)
        - Part 3, 1026a (Box 1996.IA.02-26)
        - Part 4, 1026b (Box 1996.IA.02-26)
        - Part 5, 1027 (Box 1996.IA.02-26)
    - Works in Progress lectures, 1998-1999; Series I.L.5.; (16 audiocassettes)
      Materials comprise 1998-1999 audio recordings of lectures presented at the Getty Research Institute as part of their "Works in Progress" series, which provides a forum for historians, scholars and artists to present their ongoing research to a critical audience.
      - Hahn, Francois Forster. Works in Progress Lecture, January 16, 1998; 987 (Box 1996.IA.02-24)
        Audio files not found.
      - Mack, Rainer and Sarah Morris. "A Semiotic Reading of Repetition," Works in Progress Seminar, April 24, 1998; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-24)
        - Part 1, 0990a (Box 1996.IA.02-24)
        - Part 2, 0990b (Box 1996.IA.02-24)
      - Kwon, Miwon and Russell Ferguson. "Public Art and Urban Identities," Works in Progress Seminar, May 8, 1998; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-24)
        - Part 1, 0886a (Box 1996.IA.02-24)
        - Part 2, 0886b (Box 1996.IA.02-24)
      - Holiday, Peter. Works in Progress Lecture, September 25, 1998; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-24)
        - Part 1, 0891a (Box 1996.IA.02-24)
        - Part 2, 0891b (Box 1996.IA.02-24)
      - Doherty, Brigid and David Joselit. "Montage and Mimetism of Psychotechnics," Work in Progress Lecture, October 9, 1998; (2 audiocassettes) (Box 1996.IA.02-24)
        - Part 1, 0892 (Box 1996.IA.02-24)
        - Part 2, 0893 (Box 1996.IA.02-24)
      - Stern, Lesley. Works in Progress Lecture, November 6, 1998; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-24)
        - Part 1, 0993a (Box 1996.IA.02-24)
        - Part 2, 0993b (Box 1996.IA.02-24)
      - Lavin, Sylvia and Michael Roth. Works in Progress Lecture, December 18, 1998; (2 audiocassettes) (Box 1996.IA.02-25)
        - Part 1, 0901 (Box 1996.IA.02-25)
        - Part 2, 0902 (Box 1996.IA.02-25)
      - Harrison, Thomas. Works in Progress Lecture, [1999?]; 0905; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-25)
      - Lee, Pamela. Works In Progress Lecture, February 26, 1999; (2 audiocassettes) (Box 1996.IA.02-25)
        - Part 1, 1001 (Box 1996.IA.02-25)
        - Part 2, 1002 (Box 1996.IA.02-25)
      - Monahan, Laurie J. Works in Progress Lecture, March 12, 1999; (1 audiocassette) (Box 1996.IA.02-25)
        - Part 1, 1005a (Box 1996.IA.02-25)
        - Part 2, 1005b (Box 1996.IA.02-25)
      - Mereweather, Charles. Works In Progress Lecture, April 23, 1999; (2 audiocassettes) (Box 1996.IA.02-25)
        - Part 1, 1011a (Box 1996.IA.02-25)
        - Part 2, 1011b (Box 1996.IA.02-25)
        - Part 3, 1012 (Box 1996.IA.02-25)
      - Holo, Selma. Works in Progress Lecture, May 7, 1999; (2 audiocassettes) (Box 1996.IA.02-25)
        - Part 1, 1015 (Box 1996.IA.02-25)
        - Part 2, 1016 (Box 1996.IA.02-25)
    - Lectures and presentations, 1998-1999; Series I.L.6.; (10 audiocassettes)
      Materials comprise recordings of events, lectures, and discussions held at the Getty during the scholar years 1997/1998 and 1998/1999. During this time Getty scholars in residence explored the theme of the residential scholar program Representing the Passions and studied the ways in which strong, ungovernable emotions have been represented and classified in the arts throughout the history of the arts and humanities. Lecture topics include the humanities and public culture, Ottoman culture, Sevres china furniture, Vincent Van Gogh, Hendrik Petrus Berlage, and more.